oxfordjournals.org 2017-09-03

# Privacy policy | Journals | Oxford Academic

Updated on: 11/07/2016

Effective from: 11/07/2016

This privacy policy is specific to this website ("Website") and overrides any other privacy policies appearing elsewhere on Oxford University Press websites.

Oxford University Press (“OUP”) and any company and legal entity owned or controlled by OUP from time to time are referred to in this Privacy Policy as the “OUP Group”, "we", "us" or "our". The OUP Group is committed to protecting your privacy online. This privacy policy explains how we will do this. We will review this privacy policy in the light of comments we receive so please check the latest version. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us by emailing us at [Jnls.Cust.Serv@oup.com](mailto:Jnls.Cust.Serv@oup.com).

By using the Website, you are accepting the practices described in this statement.

### **What kind of information do we collect and how do we use it?**

When you visit the Website, we may collect information and statistics that contain your identifying information. The information collected may include information relating to your behaviour and navigation on the Website including but not limited to, traffic data, location data, IP address, weblogs and other communication data and the resources that you access. We also keep details of your computer (e.g. information about your browser, computer (e.g. your operating system and settings). In addition, please note that we may combine all information (including anonymous information) which we collect about you (including those from other of our affiliates websites) so that we can better understand, and in turn, provide you and other customers with more customised and better information, products and services, viewing recommendations and advertising.

If you subscribe to or ask for further information about the Website, we ask for your name, email address, postal address, and other relevant personal information. Personal information submitted in this way is added to our access control database, hosted by a third party hosting company, and to our customer databases at our and/or our affiliates' premises. This information will be updated if you inform us of any changes.

If you are a subscriber (which may be you as an individual or an institution to which you are affiliated) (including a subscriber on a trial basis), your personal information will be used to enable us to verify that you are a subscriber and to deliver any restricted content on the Website to you.

If you sign up to receive newsletters and promotional offers, we will ask you for your email address and your name and this information will be added to our customer databases.

We may use information in our customer databases to send you information about us, our affiliates, our products and services, and our affiliates' products and services that we think may be of interest to you electronically or otherwise.

We may contact you by email to request that you provide feedback by completing surveys  on your user experience of the Website and its content. Completion of these surveys is not compulsory. Any feedback will be used for internal OUP Group purposes only and will not be shared with third parties other than those affiliates, licensors and suppliers, which assist us in making the Website available to you. 

We request personal information (such as your name, email address and other contact details) from you when you contact us with subscription management queries, technical problems, to comment on the Website, or when you ask for information about how to use the products and/or services made available on the Website. Personal information submitted by you via the "contact us" page will not be added to our customer databases and we request it simply so that we can respond to you about your query. Statistics regarding the types of queries submitted to us via the "contact us" page may be collated by us in aggregate form so that we can effectively monitor the Website and improve levels of service.

If you have asked for information or subscribed to restricted content on the Website in the past and no longer subscribe to such service and do not wish us to store information about you, please contact us and we will remove your details from our customer databases. We need to store information about current subscribers in order to fulfil our contractual requirements to you and grant you access to restricted content on the Website.

You may notify us either in writing or by telephone, fax or email that you object to being contacted or being contacted in a particular stated way. If you use more than one email address to communicate with us, please notify us of each email account you use.

### **When do we share information?**

We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We share your information within the OUP Group. We also share your information with our affiliates, licensors and suppliers, which assist us in making the Website available to you (e.g. our hosting supplier).

We publish many journals on behalf of learned societies. Where you subscribe to a journal, we may share your subscription details with the society for whom we publish the journal, which they may use to invite you to join the society, or for other conferences and events organised by or for the society.

If you sign up for services that are managed or offered by other organisations, they will obtain your information and their privacy policy may apply to you.

A number of third party websites have links on our Website. If you visit any of those websites, they may collect information. Such websites are not within our control and are not covered by this privacy policy. These websites may have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for those policies. Please check those policies before you submit any personal data to such third party websites.

Where we use third party tools, for example, Google Analytics, to assist us with the Website, these service providers may collect certain data from your visits to the Website including, for example, the web address of the page that you're visiting, and your IP address. They may also set cookies on your browser or read cookies that are already there. For further information on how Google uses this data, please go to: <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.

If we believe that your use of the Website is unlawful or damaging to others, we reserve the right to disclose the information we have obtained through the Website about you to third parties to the extent that it is reasonably necessary in our opinion to prevent, remedy or take action in relation to such conduct.

We may also disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation; in order to enforce or apply any agreements or licences with you; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of OUP, our employees, affiliates, licensors, suppliers, and/or our customers. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

If any part of our business (including those of our affiliates) is sold or integrated with another business, your details may be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchasers and their advisers.

### **Interest based advertising**

We may engage network providers to show you other products or services you may be interested in. To find out more about the identity of the advertising network provider(s) and/or how to opt-out of viewing the advert(s), please point the cursor of your mouse on the top right hand corner of the adverts(s) and left click. 

Please note these advertising network providers use “tracking cookies” as well as information collected from your browser and terminal equipment (that is, your computer, laptop, mobile phone or handheld device) when accessing the Website.

While the third party advertisers may obtain your information via their advertising network solution, we do not provide any personally identifiable information to adverting network providers or third party advertisers.

### **Use of cookies**

OUP uses "cookies" and other technologies on the Website. The terms and conditions governing OUP's use of "cookies" and such other technologies on the Website are set out in OUP's [Cookie Policy](http://global.oup.com/cookiepolicy).

By using the Website, you are agreeing to be bound by the terms of our Cookie Policy.

### **Security**

Some of your personal information is stored at a data centre managed by our third party hosting company. The data centre managed by our third party hosting company is specifically designed to be physically secure and to admit authorised personnel only, who are contractually bound to keep all of our data confidential.

Access to our customer databases is only given on a 'need to know basis'.

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us, our affiliates or for one of our suppliers. By using the Website, you consent to these transfers.

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your information including personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access

### **Updating your details**

If any of the information that you have provided to OUP changes e.g. if you change your e-mail address you may update your account details online on the Website or by contacting Customer Services on [Jnls.Cust.Serv@oup.com](mailto:Jnls.Cust.Serv@oup.com).

### **Changes to our privacy policy**

We reserve the right to make changes to this privacy policy. Any changes we may make to this privacy policy will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

### **Governing law**

You agree that this privacy policy shall be exclusively governed in accordance with the laws of and the courts in England and Wales.
